blackeyedpeas.com 2005-12-14

# BlackEyedPeas.com - The Official Black Eyed Peas Website

[Privacy Policy] - Effective: March 26, 2005

We will have the right to collect, share and use your information in accordance with our Privacy Policy, which is incorporated by reference in these Terms. In addition, the artist or band may have access to and use of information you provide in connection with your membership to the Fan Club. Use includes, but is not limited to, sending email newsletters, updates or content related to the artist or band. These messages may be required as part of membership to the Fan Club, at the discretion of the artist or band.

blackeyedpeas.com understands the concerns that its members and other users of its web site (the "Site") have about the collection, use, and disclosure of their Personal Information while online. Accordingly, we have established this Privacy Policy to make you aware of the information collection and sharing practices of the Site. This Privacy Policy only applies to transactions made and data gathered on the Site and does not apply to any other web site or offline point of contact between us and you. By visiting the Site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically as we may update it from time to time.

Your IP Address  
Like most e-commerce websites, each time you visit the Site, we automatically collect your IP address and the web page from which you came. We use this information to administer and optimize the Site for you and to diagnose problems with our Site. We use your IP address to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information about you.

Cookies  
Like most websites, the Site uses cookies to keep track of your purchases and other activity on the Site and enhance your experience on the Site. We also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, to save your password, and if you choose, to save other personal and financial information so you do not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Site. Third parties advertisers on the Site may also place cookies on your browser. If you wish to disable these cookies, the "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how. However, if you set your browser to disable cookies, you may not be able to access certain areas on the Site.

Personal Information   
In some cases, we will collect information from you that can be used to personally identify you, such as your name, address, phone number, email address, purchase history, and credit card number ("Personal Information").

We collect Personal Information when you sign up to receive newsletters, request information regarding an event we sponsor, enter contests, open an account, purchase tickets or products, and otherwise as needed to fulfill your requests for information, products, and services. When we collect this information, you will know it because you will need to submit this information to us in order to open your account or receive the information, product, or service you requested. We use your Personal Information for our internal purposes, such as maintaining the Site and fulfilling your requests for products, services, and information. For example, we will contact you when necessary in connection with events for which you purchased tickets on the Site (including event confirmations, changes and cancellations). We also use your Personal Information to send you information, offers and other promotional materials from us and selected third parties. We carefully select the information we send to you and attempt to send you offers that are of value to you, such as discounts, exclusive offers or special event information. We provide you with the option of declining to receive offers from us by "opting-out" of receipt of this type of communication. Generally, we will not send you communications on behalf of third parties unless we add our blackeyedpeas.com brand to those communications.

We share your Personal Information with our agents, representatives, contractors and service providers so they can provide us with support services such as authorization of credit card transactions, order fulfillment and sweepstakes and promotional fulfillment. We do not authorize these entities to use your information for any other purpose. If you purchase tickets on the Site, we will share your Personal Information with the venues, promoters, artists and other third parties associated with the concerts and events for which you purchase tickets ("Event Partners"). Due to our contractual obligations with Event Partners, we cannot offer you the opportunity to opt-out of our sharing of your Personal Information with them. We may select certain third parties with whom we will share your Personal Information so that they can communicate directly with you about their products and services. We attempt to carefully select these third parties and the specific offers they intend to communicate to you so that you will receive high quality, valuable and relevant offers. We generally do not authorize third parties (except our Event Partners) to communicate with you without adding our blackeyedpeas.com brand to the communication. The Site provides you with the option of declining to have your Personal Information shared with these selected third parties. We will also provide your Personal Information to a third party if you purchase products or services offered by third parties on the Site (such as magazine subscriptions). Your Personal Information may be shared with a third party in the event of a transfer of ownership, assets or a bankruptcy of blackeyedpeas.com. We may also disclose your Personal Information as required or permitted by law, to protect the interests or safety of blackeyedpeas.com or a third party, or to prevent an emergency. Any third party with whom we share your Personal Information is authorized to use your Personal Information in accordance with our contractual arrangements with such third parties and in accordance with their own privacy policies, over which we have no control. Those who contact you will need to be instructed directly by you regarding your preferences for the use of your Personal Information by them.

How We Use And When We Share Financial Information  
We use your financial information to check your qualifications and bill you for and otherwise facilitate your purchase of products and services.

When you make a purchase on the Site, we will provide your financial information to our service providers and to such third parties as we determine is necessary to process your transactions. These third parties may include the credit card companies and banking institutions used to process the transaction. Also, depending on the circumstances of our arrangements, we may share your financial information with applicable Event Partners, primarily but not exclusively for facilitating "will call" ticket pick up and dispute resolution and customer service at the event venue on the date of the event. By purchasing products or services of third parties (such as magazine subscriptions) offered on the Site, we will provide your financial information to those third parties. Any of these various third parties are authorized to use your financial information in accordance with our contractual arrangements with such third parties and in accordance with their own privacy policies, over which we have no control.

Security Precautions  
Whenever we obtain your Personal Information, we use commercially reasonable efforts to protect it from unauthorized access or disclosure. While we will use such efforts, we cannot and will not act as insurers of the security of your Personal Information transmitted over the Internet. Accordingly, we assume no liability for any disclosure of data due to errors in transmission, unauthorized third party access or other acts of third parties, or acts or omissions beyond our reasonable control. If you are a member of blackeyedpeas.coms, you should note that when you complete your "Member Profile," this information can be viewed by other members. Accordingly, you should not provide any information in your Member Profile that you do not wish to share with third parties and you should have no privacy expectations with respect to the information contained within it.

Warning About Online Disclosure of Information   
You should be aware that if you voluntarily disclose information online in a publicly accessible area, such as in your member profile, a message board or chat room, that information may be collected and used by others. We do not control the actions of our users. If you disclose Personal Information in your member profile, message board, or any other publicly accessible place on the Internet, you do so at your own risk and should understand that your submitted information may be collected and used by others to send you unsolicited messages, advertisements, or for other purposes. Please remember that protection of your privacy begins with you. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any password you use to register, and you should always be careful and responsible whenever disclosing information online.
